A Guide to the Stephen Longstreet Artwork, 1931-1972
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Stephen Longstreet Artwork 1031-1972
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
10740-c
This collection contains fourteen items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
These designs were given to the University of Virginia Library by Stephen Longstreet, Beverly Hills, California, on June 8, 1994.
Scope and Content Information
This collection consists of fourteen collage and designer marker ("magic markers") artwork designs, ca. 1931-1972, and undated, created by artist and author Stephen Longstreet (1907- ). The collages, composed of several different types of paper, including construction paper and magazines, were designed for use on the stage for the Coast Jazz Group Project "Reading Poetry to Jazz". Slides were made of several of these collages for back projection onto the stage.
Much of the designer marker artwork, which also occasionally uses india ink in the design, were selections from a limited edition of Stephen Longstreet's prints entitled Jam Sessions, which were hand colored by the artist and issued by the Los Angeles Art Association in 1952.
Contents List
- Collages
  - Dizzy Gillespie "Groovin' High" Gertrude Stein "Tender Buttons" 1972
  - Bix Beiderbecke "In A Mist" Emily Dickinson "Bolts of Memory" 1972
  - Sidney Bechet "King Porter Stomp" William Faulkner "Three Poems" 1972
  - Duke Ellington "Take the 'A' Train" Walt Whitman "Blades of Grass" 1972
  - Benny Goodman "Stompin' at the Savoy" T.S. Eliot "The Waste Land" 1972
  - Charlie Parker "How Deep is the Ocean" Edna St. Vincent Millay "Renascence" 1972
- Designer Marker Artwork
  - "Backstage - Minsky's - the Stars" 1931
  - "Bessie Smith Sketch from Life" [sic 1944]
  - "Street Singer" n.d.
  - Three Jazz Musicians 1968
  - "Jam Session" n.d.
  - "Late Hours Harlem 1947" 1947
  - "Rainbow Room" n.d.
  - "Blowing Fine" n.d.